[Music]
many of the diseases that cause a
constant drain on healthcare budgets can
be prevented by proper nutrition so why
aren't the big payers getting involved i
mean even like a one percent decline in
excess body fat could alone save tens of
billions
you'd think at least the health
insurance industry would try to get
people to eat healthier to try to pay
out less money
well
one could say the insurance industry
actually
benefits from high health care costs
because these rising costs are simply
passed on to both individuals and
employers in terms of higher premiums
and insurers take a fixed percentage of
these premiums as increasing profits
they get a piece of the pie
so the bigger the pie the unhealthier
everyone is the bigger their peace
as such insurers have not done as much
as they could to help reduce healthcare
costs because lower costs would hurt
their bottom line
what if there was a medication that
could successfully treat and even
reverse heart disease type 2 diabetes
high blood pressure many other chronic
conditions without any negative side
effects and offered the promise of
dramatically reduced health care costs
imagine all the advertising there would
be to promote it imagine how much they
would charge a drug that could not just
treat but cure diabetes and these other
diseases
then what if you were told that
medication exists today is available to
everyone in unlimited quantities at a
low cost but the vast majority of the
american public has never heard about it
you want a solution to significantly
reduce health care costs the solution
is to use food as medical treatment
specifically foods
made from minimally processed plants
one of the main barriers is simply the
current widespread belief that once
someone has a chronic condition such as
heart disease type 2 diabetes
there's very little that can be done to
actually reverse the disease and the
best outcome possible is to maintain the
condition so that it just doesn't get
any worse
the fact that a whole food plant-based
approach provides a safe effective
low-cost alternative to not just
eliminating symptoms but potentially
reversing the underlying condition
without drugs or surgery is unknown to a
vast majority of americans in contrast
to the pharmaceutical industry that
spends large sums to market new drugs
there are not big profits in promoting a
plant-based diet
the politics surrounding healthcare is
who's going to pay for it instead of
what kind of healthcare is best and the
evidence is overwhelming that a whole
food plant-based diet provides the best
opportunity to not only reduce the
growth in spending but actually decrease
total health care costs more than any
drug medical procedure insurance reform
or provider payment model out there
thankfully
the word is spreading a review of the
evidence published in kaiser
permanente's journal concluded that
physicians should consider recommending
a plant-based diet to all their patients
especially those with high blood
pressure diabetes cardiovascular disease
or obesity
kaiser has followed up with
user-friendly guides freely available
online for both physicians and patients
explaining the benefits and practical
aspects of implementing a plant-based
diet so hey why aren't all insurers
sending out such information to all
their members right
you know how all the drug ads are like
ask your doctor if this drug is right
for you well you know members could be
prompted to ask their physicians about
the ability of plant-based diets to
reduce or eliminate prescription drug
use reverse disease
of course these materials would also
have to list all the side effects side
effects include
increased energy lower blood pressure
improve digestion all while eating
unlimited quantities of satisfying food
ask your doctor if plants
are right for you
[Music]
you